site-closed.wikispaces.com 2018-10-08

# Privacy Policy | Tes

###  Privacy Policy 

Tes Global Limited (" **we** ", " **our** " or " **Tes** ") is committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals in respect of whom we hold personal information. Tes includes our trading activities that are branded Tes and also Times Higher Education (also referred to as THE). Please read the following Privacy Policy which explains how we use and protect your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to use of all our services and websites (and web-based services) on which a link to this policy appears (the " **Sites** ").

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 or any replacement legislation including the EU General Data Protection Regulation (the " **GDPR** ") (together, the “ **Data Protection Legislation** ”), the data controller is Tes Global Limited of 26 Red Lion Square, London, WC1R 4HQ, United Kingdom.

We take your privacy seriously and we are committed to keeping your information private. To the extent we are required by law, we have notified the United Kingdom's Information Commissioner's Office that we will process your personal information in accordance with the Data Protection Legislation (as defined above).

By providing us with any information about yourself (including via the Sites), you consent to our processing of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Cookies Policy.

###  This Privacy Policy covers 

  1. What personal information we collect about you and how we collect it 
  2. How we use your personal information 
  3. Personal information that we share with third parties 
  4. Our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information
  5. Data retention, data security and transfers of personal information outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) 
  6. Your rights
  7. Accessing and updating your personal information 
  8. How to unsubscribe from any email alerts that you receive 
  9. Changes to our Privacy Policy
  10. Legal and Contact Information

###  1\. What personal information we collect about you and how we collect it 

#### Information that you provide us directly

We collect personal information whenever you contact us and provide us with information that we are able to identify you by, including when you contact us by phone, email or when you sign up to use any of our services. In particular, we collect information about you when you register and create a Tes and/or THE account, post content on any of our Sites (such as on any forums or chatrooms), upload your CV, purchase a product from us (such as through the Tes Store), subscribe to receive a product or service that we offer (for example, a magazine subscription), subscribe to receive email updates from us, take part in a competition or market research and every time you e-mail us directly. We also collect information about the payment methods that you use for any transactions that you make with us. 

####   
_Content posted by you containing personal information_

If you post any personal information to any of our public forums, this information will immediately be made available to other users throughout the world who may use it to send you unsolicited communications. In some circumstances we may display pseudonyms that identify you as a user but not your actual personal information (your username for example) when you post material to the Sites to allow users to identify each other.

####   
Information that we automatically collect (including use of "cookies")

We automatically gather certain limited information about your visits to our Sites. This includes demographic data and browsing patterns. Information automatically received includes your: IP address (which identifies the computer or device that you use to access the Sites); the time and date of your visit; browser; operating system; internet connection details, as well as a breakdown of your journey through our Sites and products that you searched for. This is used to build up marketing profiles, to aid strategic development, to manage our relationship with advertisers and to audit usage of the Sites. 

####   
_Use of Cookies_

In particular, we use cookies to collect this information. A cookie is a small collection of data sent by a web server to a web browser, which lets the server collect information back from the browser. Our use of cookies also may allow registered users to be presented with a personalised version of the Sites.

Our Sites use ad servers (such as "Doubleclick") to serve the advertisements that you see on pages from our Sites. That partner uses cookies to collect information about your use of our Sites to help target ads to your interests. To find out more about the use of cookies and the information-gathering practices and opt-out procedures of DoubleClick please go to <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy>.  

Please note that if you do disable cookies, certain services on our Sites may not be available. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences. If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use products or services that require you to "sign in" and you may not be able to take full advantage of offerings or use on all our Sites.

For further information please see our Cookies Policy https://www.tes.com/terms/cookies-policy and for more independent information about cookies, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

####   
Information that we collect from third parties

Certain third party partners of Tes may provide us with information relating to you. It is that third party's responsibility to ensure that it has obtained your consent to do this. However, where possible, we will request from our partners that they have the right to pass on this information.

###  2\. How we use your personal information 

We will use your personal information to enable us to provide our Services to you and enable you to use the Sites, including, for the following purposes: 

  * to authenticate your identity and administer your Tes and/or THE account;
  * to personalise aspects of our services;
  * to deal with your enquiries and requests;
  * to process your orders for any services or products that you purchase from us; and
  * to enable our data processors (such as our group companies and hosting providers) to provide services (or components thereof) requested by you. 

Additionally, where you have provided us with consent, we will also use your personal information for certain other purposes, including:

  * to share with recruitment institutions (if you are applying for a job); 
  * to contact you about opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you and to provide you with updates about developments on the Sites and information about the products and services we offer;
  * to carry out market research or surveys; 
  * for marketing and strategic development purposes, for example to identify trends usage; and
  * to enable third parties to contact you in relation to services offered in conjunction with us or in respect of services that they provide. 

It is your responsibility to ensure that any information submitted as part of the registration process to your user account or as part of an application to a job posting is accurate and up to date.

###  3\. Personal information that we share with third parties 

In order to provide the services offered on our Sites, we sometimes need to share your personal information with other companies in the Tes group. However, we will continue to be responsible for the usage and security of your personal information when this happens. 

#### _Tes' data processors_

We may also share your personal information with third party processors or suppliers that we engage to provide services to us and/or support our offering to you (such as our hosting providers). These third parties may need to process your personal information on our behalf to provide such services. Where this is the case we take great care to only appoint reliable third parties who can guarantee the security of your personal information and our business information. For example, we ask each such third party to complete an information security questionnaire to ensure their practices and procedures provide the level of security that we would expect (and is required under law) when processing personal information.  Note that these third parties simply process personal information on behalf of Tes and have no right to use, disclose or transfer your personal information in any other way. Please see below in relation to our policy for transfers of personal information outside the EEA.

#### _Third parties that we share your personal information with  _

Where you have provided us with consent, we will share your personal information with other third parties (who will also be data controllers in respect of the information that we share). For example, some of our Sites and services are hosted by us on behalf of those recruiting institutions that have signed-up to process job vacancies and applications via the service (for example <https://www.tes.com/recruit/school-portal)>. To the extent you have any concerns about an institution's handling of your personal information you should get in touch with that institution.

#### _Other circumstances where use or share your personal information_

In certain circumstances, we may be required at law to disclose your personal information to third parties such as government bodies, law enforcement agencies, and data protection regulators.

###  4\. Our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information 

We are required to collect and use personal information in accordance with, and in a manner justified by, the Data Protection Legislation. In doing so, we rely on one or more of the following grounds to legally collect and use your personal information:

  * we may process your personal information where this is necessary for the performance of the contract which we have with you (i.e. to provide our services to you);
  * we may process your personal information where you have consented to us doing so; and/or
  * we may process your personal information where it is in our legitimate interests to do so, for example:
  * to analyse and create statistical reports based on the services we provide and our performance of those services; and
  * for the proper keeping of business records.

Where we rely on your consent to process any of your personal information, you may revoke your consent at any time. Any such revocation will not affect the lawfulness of any prior use of that personal information.

###  5\. Data retention, data security and transfers of personal information outside of the European Economic Area (EEA) 

We take steps to protect your personal information from unauthorised access and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage. We will only keep your personal information for as long as we reasonably require and, in any event, only for as long as Data Protection Legislation allows.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will take steps to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted via email and/or our website; any transmission is at your own risk. 

The personal information that we collect from you will, where possible, be stored and processed within the EEA. In certain circumstances, we may require third parties that are based outside of the EEA to process, host or store your personal information and by submitting your personal information to us, you are acknowledging this transfer, storing or processing. Please note that countries outside the EEA may not have the same standard of data protection legislation as countries within the EEA.   

In the event your personal information is transferred, stored or processed outside of the EEA, we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Data Protection Legislation.  This means that we will only allow third parties to access your personal information where those third parties (a) are in countries that have been confirmed by the European Commission to provide adequate protection to personal information; or (b) have agreed to provide all protections to your personal information as set out in the Data Protection Legislation (such as by entering into the European Commission's Model Clauses).

###  6\. Your rights 

Should you have any queries or complaints in relation to how we use your information, please contact us via the details set out at section 10 below.  Should you wish to take any complaints or queries further, you have the right to contact the Information Commissioner's Office regarding such issues. Further information about how to make a complaint can be obtained at [www.ico.org.uk ](http://www.ico.org.uk/)or by telephoning 0303 123 1113.

###  7\. Accessing and updating your personal information 

You have the right to see the personal information we hold about you and to ask us to: (a) make any changes to ensure that any personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date; (b) erase or stop processing any personal information we hold about you where there is no longer a legal ground for us to hold it; or (c) transfer any information we hold about you to a specified third party. If you wish to do this, please contact us using the contact details set out below. We may charge a £10 fee for complying with some of the requests made under this section if they are made before 25 May 2018.

###  8\. How to unsubscribe from any email alerts that you receive 

If you have elected to receive information about our products or services or the products or services offered jointly with or on behalf of other organisations and/or "alerts" from us via email (for example, by creating an email alert for a job) and would like at any time to unsubscribe from this service, please email us at [help@tes.com](mailto:help@tes.com) or click on the " **unsubscribe** " link at the bottom of an email.

###  9\. Changes to our Privacy Policy 

Tes may amend this Privacy Policy at any time and where we make material changes to it we will provide notice on our website. By continuing to use our services and/or our Sites, you agree to the updated Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to any changes that we make, you should not use or access (or continue to use or access) our services and/or our Sites.

###  10\. Legal and Contact Information 

The registered office of Tes Global Limited is:

Tes Global Limited  
26 Red Lion Square  
London WC1R 4HQ  
United Kingdom

We will use all reasonable efforts to answer any questions or resolve any concerns regarding your privacy promptly.

All comments, queries and requests relating to our use of your personal information are welcomed (including in relation to transfers of personal information outside the EEA). If you would like to contact us, queries should be addressed to Customer Services at the above address; or by email at [help@tes.com](mailto:help@tes.com).
